appliedbank.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy - Applied Bank

This Privacy Policy is provided to help you understand how we protect Customer information. Applied Bank (herein referred to as Bank, we, us or our) respects your decision to do business with us and takes your privacy seriously. Our Privacy Policy provides you with an opportunity to make informed choices about the management of personal information. You trust us with your personal and financial information and we'll honor that trust by handling your information carefully and sensibly. This Privacy Policy will help you understand how we safeguard and use information, and how it applies to all Customers or former Customers who obtain financial services from us for personal, family or household purposes. Similarly, our Customers who receive information from us or transact business with us through the Internet are covered by additional privacy policies on our websites.

  * Collection of Information
  * Security Procedures
  * Disclosures to Service Your Account
  * Disclosures to Provide You with Offers for Products and Services
  * Offers for Products and Services of Other Companies
  * Vermont Residents Only
  * Protecting Our Children
  * Former Customers
  * Commitment to Service  

  * Online Privacy Addendum
  * Information Usage
  * Links to Third Party Websites  

  * Legal Disclaimers
  * Controls

## Collection of Information

We collect information from and about you in order to identify you as our Customer, establish and manage Customer accounts, complete Customer transactions, understand Customer needs, market products and services we believe are of value to Customers, and comply with legal and regulatory requirements. We collect and obtain Customer information from various sources including the following:

  * Information listed on credit applications or other related forms
  * Information listed on deposit account opening forms
  * Enrollment in Online Banking
  * Credit reporting agencies
  * Customer transactions with us or other institutions
  * Customer communications with the Bank or any of its affiliates
  * Public information

## Security Procedures

We are committed to maintaining the security of our Customers’ financial and personal information. All operational and data processing systems are in a secure environment that protects Customer information from being accessed by unauthorized individuals or third parties. Access to nonpublic information about you is restricted to those Associates who need to know that information in order to provide products or services to you. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal standards to guard your nonpublic personal information. Correspondence and telephone conversations are monitored for quality, compliance, and accuracy to ensure that our standards are being followed.

From time to time, we may enter into agreements with other companies to provide services to us or to make products and services available to you. Under these agreements, the companies may receive information about you. They must safeguard this information, and they may not use it for any other purpose.

## Disclosures to Service Your Account

It is often necessary for us to disclose Customer information to companies, including our affiliates, which perform services necessary to establish and manage Customer accounts on our behalf. These services may include transaction and statement processing, research and analysis, delivery of benefits and programs, marketing services, card issuance, Customer Service, and protection against fraud. Additionally, if we offer Customers the opportunity to enroll in affinity, frequent user, or award programs, we may provide certain Customer information to companies that administer such programs. When it comes to disclosing Customer information to others for the purpose of establishing and managing Customer accounts, we place limits on who receives specific information. We disclose to these companies information that they need to establish and manage Customer accounts and restrict the use of that information so that it cannot be used for any purpose beyond the intended service. We may also provide certain Customer information to others outside of the Bank as required or permitted by law, such as to government entities, other third parties in response to subpoenas, or to consumer reporting agencies.

## Disclosures to Provide You with Offers for Products and Services

We do not disclose any Customer information to anyone, except as permitted by law. However, we recognize that an important benefit for our Customers is the opportunity to receive offers for products and services from other companies that may work with us. In the future, we may provide these offers to Customer when we believe they will find them of value. These offers will be developed under conditions designed to safeguard Customer information.

## Offers for Products and Services of Other Companies

As described in this Privacy Policy, we work with affiliated and non-affiliated companies that help us service your account, and disclose information to these companies as permitted by law. In the future, we also may work with other companies to provide our Customer with offers for products and services that they provide. These other companies may include financial service providers (that offer for example, insurance, loan and investment products) and non-financial companies (that offer for example card registries, membership clubs, and other consumer products and services). Unless you direct us not to, we may disclose information about you to those companies to enable them to develop and deliver these offers to you.

If you prefer, you may tell us not to disclose information about you to other companies for the purpose of providing you with their products and services; you can write to the Bank c/o P.O. Box 17125, Wilmington, DE 19850-7125 (“opt-out”). Please include your Applied Bank Account Number(s) in your letter. If you opt out, everyone associated with your account will be excluded as well. If you have more than one account with us, you may receive multiple copies of this Privacy Policy. In that event, you will need to separately opt-out of this information disclosure for each of your accounts with us.

If you opt-out, you may still receive offers for products and services provided by affiliated or non-affiliated companies when we communicate with you about your account. These offers, however, will be developed without disclosing information about you to the other companies. You may also still receive offers that are developed without the use of information that we have collected about you.

## Vermont Residents Only

We will not disclose information about you to other companies for the purpose of providing you with their products and services unless you authorize us to do so (“opt-in”). You may opt-in by writing to the Bank c/o 17125, Wilmington, DE 19850-7125 or by contacting our Customer Service Department at 800-947-1090.

Even if you do not opt-in, you may still receive offers for products and services provided by affiliated or non-affiliated companies when we communicate with you about your account. These offers, however, will be developed without disclosing information about you to the other companies.

If you elect to opt-in and subsequently decide to revoke the opt-in direction you have given to us, you can write to the Bank c/o P.O. Box 17125, Wilmington, DE 19850-7125 or contact our Customer Service Department at 800-947-1090.

## Protecting Our Children

We do not knowingly market to children. We recognize the importance of protecting children's identities and privacy.

## Former Customers

If you decide to close your account or your account becomes inactive or is closed for some other reason, we will continue to treat and safeguard your information as described in this Privacy Policy.

## Commitment to Service

We believe the confidentiality and protection of Customer information is one of our fundamental responsibilities. While information is critical to providing quality service, we recognize that one of our most important assets is our Customers’ trust. Thus, the safekeeping of Customer information is a priority for us. We will continuously strive to maintain complete and accurate information about our Customers and their accounts. If you believe that our records contain inaccurate or incomplete information about you, it is important that you notify us as soon as possible. We will investigate your concerns and correct any inaccuracies.

This Privacy Policy replaces any prior privacy policy we have posted or delivered to you. We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time, and we will inform you of changes as required by law.

## Online Privacy Addendum

**This document is an addendum to the Applied Bank Privacy Policy covering our Customers who receive information or transact business with us over the Internet.**

Through our website, we strive to provide valuable information to you about the Bank and how we may serve you. In addition, we make available timely updates on new products, services, locations, and Customer Service hours for our valued Customers. We also provide timely account information for users of online banking and the ability to make online payments.

We safeguard all information our Customers share with us through our website.

## Information Usage

Any information you choose to provide us may be used to improve the content and services offered on our website, as well as to contact you with more information about our products, services, or upcoming events.

## Links to Third Party Websites

The Applied Bank website contains links to, and may be linked from, third party websites, which are not under the control of Applied Bank. Applied Bank makes no representations whatsoever about any other website to which you may have access through, or to, the Applied Bank website. When you access a non-Applied Bank website, you do so at your own risk, and Applied Bank is not responsible for the accuracy or reliability of any information, data, opinions, advice, or statements made on these sites. Applied Bank is not responsible for updating or correcting false or misleading information on any third party website. Applied Bank provides these links merely as a convenience, and the inclusion of such links does not imply that Applied Bank endorses or accepts any responsibility for the content or uses of such websites. Furthermore, any opinions expressed on any third party website are not necessarily those of Applied Bank.

## Legal Disclaimers

All information on this website is protected by copyright in the United States of America and in other countries. Unless otherwise specified, no one has permission to copy or republish, in any form, any information found on this website.

The posting of information or other materials to this website does not constitute a waiver of any proprietary right in such information and materials (such as, but not limited to, copyright, service marks, trademarks, trade names, or other intellectual property) and does not transfer any rights to a user of the website or any other third party, except as expressly provided herein.

## Controls

All content on Applied Bank's website is owned by Applied Bank. Any changes to the site are made solely through the Bank's request and are completed by Applied Bank or entities that we have authorized only. Any credit card, loan or deposit application/account opening form that is altered in any way will not be accepted.

Applied Bank is not responsible for system errors on your computer that prevent the Bank's website from loading or operating properly. If an error is discovered within Applied Bank's website itself or due to a problem at the Bank's Internet Service Provider, Applied Bank and the Internet Service Provider will correct the error as soon as possible.

This is the official website of Applied Bank.
